Guide to the John P. Shacochis papers, 1964-1986
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
John P. Shacochis papers
1964-1986
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
John P. Shacochis
C0026
7 linear feet (20 boxes)
Materials include daily logs, correspondence, photographs, campaign materials, and reports from Shacochis' career with the Navy, Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, and various boards and committees he served on.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by John P. Shacochis in 1991.
Biographical Information
John P. Shacochis was born May 30, 1915 in West Pittson, Pennsylvania. Mr. Shacochis began his thirty-three year career with the Federal Government in 1940. During these years he worked for the Social Security Administration, Veterans Administration, Salary Stabilization Board, and for twenty years, as a Management Engineer with the Bureau of Naval Personnel. In 1973, Mr. Shacochis became a Community Planner for Fairfax County, Virginia, and in 1975 was elected Supervisor for the Dranesville District. He served as supervisor until December 31, 1979. During his term he served as a member of the Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, Northern Virginia Transportation Commission, Fairfax County Transportation Safety Commission, Board of Supervisors Fire and Police Committee, Fairfax County/Fairfax City Liaison Committee, COG Air Quality Commission, and Fairfax County Ad Hoc Committee for Prevention of Drug Abuse. He also served on the boards of the Washington Area Transit Authority and Fairfax Hospital Association.
Scope and Content
Materials include daily logs, correspondence, photographs, campaign materials, and reports from Shacochis' career with the Navy, Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, and various boards and committees he served on.
Arrangement
Organized into three series.
Series 1: Federal Civil Service, 1944-1972 (Boxes 1-4)
Series 2: Fairfax County Civic Association, 1962-1986 (Boxes 5-20)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other Northern Virginia personal and organizational political collections.
Index Terms
Persons:
Shacochis, John P., 1915-
Corporate Names:
Fairfax County (Va.). Board of Supervisors.; United States. Navy.
Contents List
- Series 1: Federal Civil Service, 1944-1972; (4 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Performance Indicators - Civil Service (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Presentation of Ideas (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Naval Manpower Information System (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Terminal Digit Filing Systems (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report of Management Survey, July, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Top Management Seminar (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Top Management Seminar (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - report of Management Survey, March, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Navy Management Review, January, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Vol. VI, No. 1
  - Bureau of Personnel Organization Charts and Functional Statements (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Naval Personnel Management Study Guide (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Management Review of the Department of the Navy, Final Report, September 4, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Organization and Staffing of Naval Reserve and Training Departments (Box 2, Folder 7)
    And other organizational elements at CONUS Naval District Headquarters.
  - Review of Bupers Sponsored Elements of CONUS Naval District Headquarters, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Work Simplification for Naval Units, March, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Role of Bupers in Relation to Fundamental Objections of the Department of the Navy (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bupers Management Information System Task Force, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Philippine Navy Study (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Casualty Reporting Study (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vietnamese Navy Organization Report (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bupers Management Information Study (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Microfile Conversion Task Force (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes slides.
  - Report of Microfile Conversion Task Force, May, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Streamlining Paper Work Processing (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Collection of Papers on Management Science (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Fairfax County Civic Association, 1962-1986; (16 boxes)
  - Town of Lewinsville (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dranesville Independent Force (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hamnel Tract - Lewinsville (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - West Park Re zoning (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mclean Citizens Reston (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Declaration of Candidacy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Treasurer, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Plan, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Speeches and Policy Statements, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Information System, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Questionnaires, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Contributions Report, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Spending, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Victory Congratulations, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Sample Ballots, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Demographics, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - campaign Headquarters Log, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Name Listings, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Rufus Phillips, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Vote Count, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - election contestation, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Board of Supervisors Certificate, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Daily Logs, January, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Daily Logs, February, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Daily Logs, March, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Daily Logs, April, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Daily Logs, May, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Daily Logs, June, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Daily Logs, July, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Daily Logs, August, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Daily Logs, September, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Daily Logs, October, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Daily Logs, November, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Daily Logs, December, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Daily Logs, January, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Daily Logs, February, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Daily Logs, March, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Daily Logs, April, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Daily Logs, May, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Daily Logs, June, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Daily Logs, July, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Daily Logs, August, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Daily Logs, September, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Daily Logs, October, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Daily Logs, November, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Daily Logs, December, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Daily Logs, January, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Daily Logs, February, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Daily Logs, March, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Daily Logs, April, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Daily Logs, May, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Daily Logs, June, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Daily Logs, July, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Daily Logs, August, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Daily Logs, September, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Daily Logs, October, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Daily Logs, November, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Daily Logs, December, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Daily Logs, January, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Daily Logs, February, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Daily Logs, March, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Daily Logs, April, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Daily Logs, May, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Daily Logs, June, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Daily Logs, July, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Daily Logs, August, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Daily Logs, September, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Daily Logs, October, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Daily Logs, November, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Daily Logs, December, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Weekly Schedules, January, 1976-December, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, February, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, April, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, June, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, July, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, August, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, September, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, October, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, November, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, December, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, January, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, February, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, March, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, April, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, October, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, November, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, December, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, February, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, March, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, April, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, May, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, June, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, July, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, August, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, September, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, October, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, November, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, December, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, January, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, February, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, March, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, April, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, October, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, November, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, December, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Old Chesterbrook Road Bridge Controversy (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Goals for the Dranesville District (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - FAR Plan for Noise Abatement (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Restudy - McLean Central Business District (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cost of Housing Study (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Transportation Safety Commission (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Great Falls Street (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Balanced Transportation System (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Council of Government (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax Hospital Association (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Wolf Trap Farm Park (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Appointment to George Mason University Board of Visitors (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Salvation Army (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Appreciation and Commendation (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - To the Citizens of Fairfax County in the Year 2076 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County Board of Supervisors Meeting, January 31, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Transcript of meeting, board comments on sewer service charges
  - Northern Virginia People, September - October, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Employment History (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - News Items and Letters on Shacochis Resignation from Board (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Politics of Confrontation in the Suburbs", May 5, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Copy of a portion of Washington Post article.
  - Fairfax County Police Association, Inc. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Citation for Meritorious Service and Loyal Cooperation
  - Fairfax County Planning Commission "Historical Highlights" (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Family Life Curriculum (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Letter to the editor
  - News clippings - Sound of McLean - "From the Office of John P. Shacochis" (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - News clippings, Pre-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - News clippings, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - News clippings, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - News clippings, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - News clippings, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - News clippings, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - News clippings Marrywood (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - News clippings Marrywood (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - News clippings Dranesville Independent Force (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - John P. Shacochis, Sr. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Photograph, Black and White Portrait
  - Vice Admiral Bagley presents "Superior Civilian Service Award" to John Shacochis, June, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Photograph, Black and White
  - Campaign, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Metro Officials Cut Ribbon on Opening Day, March 27, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Operating Bull-Dozer with Giuseppe Cecchi at Ground breaking for the Rotunda at Tysons Corner, June, 15, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Town Seal, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Mr. Harry Richards, council member from Dyfed, Wales, presents Town Seal to Host John Shacochis and Acting Board Chairman Martha Pennino. Photograph, Black and White
  - Ground breaking for Dulles International Aeronational Aeroservices, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - First Ride on Rosslyn's Escalator, January 6, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Second longest in the world. Photograph, Black and White
  - First Metro Train Ride under Potomac River, January 6, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    District of Columbia to Rosslyn, Virginia. Photograph, Black and White
  - Wills of Martha and George Washington Are Transferred to Mount Vernon, July, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Jim Hoognagle and John Shacochis participate in ceremony. Photograph, Black and White
  - Von Meister Reception for Callahan Campaign, September 29, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Helen Shacochis greets John and Liz Warner. Photograph, Black and White
  - Von Meister Reception for Callahan Campaign, September 29, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Liz Warner. Photograph, Color
  - Metropolitan Washington Council of Government, December, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    John Shacochis speaking at annual meeting. Photograph, Black and White
  - Opening of Silver Spring Metro Station, February 3, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Supervisor Shacochis speaks. Photograph, Black and White
  - Herrity, J.I. Wood member of City Council, September, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Ealing, London UK - Supervisor Shacochis, discuss Fairfax County Government Policies with Leonard Whorton, County Executive. Photograph, Black and White
  - Ground Breaking Ceremony for Potomac Intake Water Plant (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Fairfax County Water Authority. Photograph, Black and White
  - Frank Spandaro, September 27, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    Spandaro receives "Top Bus Driver in North America" award at APIA conference in Toronto, Canada. Photograph, Black and White
  - Commemoration of Wiehle Avenue Bridge Opening, September 20, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    Driving a golden spike with Fran Steinbauer. Photograph, Black and White
  - John Warner Visits Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, November 20, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - COG Annual Meeting, December, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    Prince George's County Executive Larry Hogan, Montgomery County Executive Charles Gilchrist, Washington. D.C. Mayor Walter Washington and COG Vice-Chairman John Shacochis. Photograph, Black and White
  - Opening of New Carrolton Metro Station, November 17, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    John P. Shacochis Sr. speaking in Prince George's County, Maryland. Photograph, Black and White
  - Annual COG Meeting, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Fairfax City Council Member Suzanne Max and Supervisors Shacochis and Pennino. Photograph, Black and White
  - Heart Fund Ball, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Billy Kilmer, Mary Lane, John and Helen Shacochis. Photograph, Black and White
  - Opening Ceremony of Virginia Little League State Tournament, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    With Lt. Governor Chuck Robb and Chairman Jack Herrity. Photograph, Color
  - Governor Dalton Signs the Dulles Toll Road Bill in Richmond, March 13, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - WMATA Board of Directors, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Washington and Lee Savings and Loan Association, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Ribbon cutting and reception at McLean Branch. Photograph, Black and White
  - Re/Max, Ltd. McLean Professional Office Park, May 20, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Ribbon cutting and reception with Dave and Bill Lunger. Photograph, Black and White
  - President Jimmy Carter Signs Metro Appropriation Bill, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    Photograph, Color
  - Supervisor John P. and Helen Shacochis and Governor John Dalton, September 20, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Herndon, Virginia. Photograph, Color
  - Breda Plant in Pistoia, Italy, October, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    WMATA officials and spouses are greeted by Breda officials. Photograph, Black and White
  - Metro Officials Visit Breda Corp. Facilities in Pistoia, Italy, October, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - METRORAIL Opens Operating on Service on Red and Blue Lines, September, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Annual COG Meeting, December, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    COG Vice-Chairman Shacochis greets President Martha Pennino, Montgomery County Council Chairman Neil Potter, and Falls Church City Mayor Harold Miller. Photograph, Black and White
  - Supervisor John Shacochis Retires from the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, December, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    Chairman Herrity presents a certificate of appreciation. Photograph, Black and White
  - Opening of the Springfield/Tysons Fire House, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    Supervisor John Shacochis cuts ribbon. Photograph, Black and White
  - Dedication of Westpark Hotel, Tysons Corner, February 2, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    Chairman Jack Herrity, Mr. Offutt, Supervisor Shacochis cutting ribbon. Photograph, Color
  - Beverly Sills, John Shacochis at Wolf Trap, July, 23, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    The final night of her singing career. Photograph, Black and White
  - Catherine Shouse, John Shacochis at Wolf Trap, July 23, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Opening Party of Fair Oaks Mall (Box 19, Folder 40)
    Helen and John Shacochis, Thomas Hirst, Jack Herrity. Photograph, Black and White
  - Chairman of METRO Board Cleatus Barnett Presents Certificate of Appreciation and Plaque to Supervisor John Shacochis (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Opening of METRO Station Van Ness, September 5, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    General Manager Richard Page, Joe Alexander, and John Shacochis. Photograph, Color
  - Board of Visitors, George Mason University, July, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    George Mason University Rector, Harriet Bradley, welcomes the new members. Photograph, Black and White
  - Former Rector, George Mason University, Harriet Bradley chats with Vice-Rector, John Shacochis, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - John Shacochis and Senator Barry Goldwater, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    At Senator John Warner's home "Atoka". Photograph, Black and White
  - Campaign Posters, 1975 (Box 20)
    See also OS 2-1 top shelf.